There is one very powerful
anti-inflammatory food that is going to
surprise you and I wish I knew about
this a long time ago when I had my
inflammation. I had a lot of gut
inflammation and you can apply this to
any inflammation. This also applies to
people with autoimmune diseases and
anyone with a condition that is itis
which is inflammation of fill in the
blank. Now there is a huge connection
and relationship between inflammation in
your joints and inflammation in the gut.
Many joint inflammatory processes,
including many autoimmune diseases,
originate in the gut. And I'm going to
go through the foods that you should
avoid first, okay? And then I'm going to
tell you what you should be eating. But
the foods that create the most
inflammation would be related to
something like gluten, which actually is
in grains. Most of the grains create
inflammation in your gut. Most people
with arthritis uh don't know it, but
their grains that they're eating are
creating a lot of inflammation. Then you
have the obvious things like alcohol,
sugar, junk foods. Another name for junk
foods would be ultrarocessed foods. Did
you realize that 83% of all the calories
in the grocery store are ultrarocessed
foods? And we wonder why our digestive
system is so messed up. Now, we also
have corn. Okay, corn is very
inflammatory. It's usually in some type
of processed refined corn product or
high fructose corn syrup, but I think
about like 90 uh 6% of all corn is
genetically modified, which means it
could have traces of glyosate, which is
considered an antibiotic. It can
actually mess with your gut flora and
create other issues. And then we have
soy, the same boat. Most soy is
genetically modified and soy and corn
have lectins which also irritate your
gut which then can stir up the
inflammation. And by the way, corn is
not a vegetable, it's a grain. Okay? And
we eat corn in so many different things.
Corn chips, tortillas, it's in a lot of
foods, especially at the grocery store.
And it's not in a whole form. It's in
some type of refined form. There's even
a new type of um genetically modified
corn that we have not really done the
safety test yet and that's going to be
very interesting what happens with that
one. And then of course we have the the
obvious seed oils too like canola oil,
the soy oil, the corn oil, all the oils
that are highly refined, they're omega6,
they're inflammatory. We also have the
A1 milk proteins. Okay, you always want
to get A2. A very safe way to avoid the
A1 is to have like milk products from
either goats or sheep as in sheep or
goat cheese or sheep or goat kefir. Both
of those products are fermented and they
have additional benefits and both of
them are the A2 type protein. But I will
say that a lot of people have casein
allergies and that is the problem. But
then again they also might have a
lactose milk sugar intolerance. Okay.
And that creates another issue. The same
thing with gluten. You don't necessarily
have to have an allergy. It could just
be a gluten intolerance. And then we
have just fiber in general. Not to
mention all the new functional fibers
that they're coming out with like the
cable corn fiber or the tapioca fiber.
All these different fiber products that
are supposedly going to be good for you,
but they create more bloating and
inflammation. If you have inflammation,
wherever it is, and if it's especially
in the gut, you need to avoid fiber. And
that includes all fiber and especially
the so-called healthy like plant
proteins and beans and legumes and even
vegetables. That's going to actually
irritate your colon. You should probably
do carnivore for a while and you'll
probably feel a lot better. But I just
listed all of the foods that greatly
contribute to inflammation. So now let's
talk about the most important food to
get rid of your inflammation. This food
has a very high level of glutamine. In
fact, if you look at all the foods out
there with the highest level of
glutamine, it would be this food. But
let me just explain what glutamine is.
It's an amino acid for your colon cells,
which is a single layer of cells that
line the inside of your colon. This
forms the barrier to your immune system
deeper inside. But your intestinal cells
are very hungry for glutamine. In fact,
out of all the glutamine, they hog like
30% of it, okay, for themselves.
Glutamine is very important in producing
ATP energy. Glutamine fuels the
intestinal layer of the cells as well as
the mucosal layer where all the good
bacteria hang out. And glutamine
supports tight junctions. You see, I
originally talked about this gut being a
source of inflammation, but I didn't
describe exactly what's occurring.
What's occurring is leaky gut, which is
intestinal hypermeability. You basically
have holes in this single layer cell
that goes right in and larger molecules
of food that are not broken down can get
through there and then your immune
system tags them as a foreign entity to
be destroyed and that's when you start
developing antibodies and allergies
against foods. So this problem really is
a bypass of normal immigration. it
doesn't give the normal stamp of
approval through the immune system and
it gets through and it creates a lot of
problems for you. So all of those bad
foods I talked about kind of put a hole
through your intestine and glutamine is
the solution for that. But now the
question is what food has the most
glutamine? And the answer is
meat, specifically beef. The thing that
they're trying to get rid of right now.
They're trying to get rid of cows
because of just some ridiculous reason.
But beef gives you a superhealing
protein, glutamine, that can greatly
support your gut and other types of
inflammatory conditions, whether you
have an autoimmune or some other type of
non-autoimmune joint problem or
whatever. Now, you can actually take
glutamine as well, but beef is the best
anti-inflammatory food that you can
possibly eat. In fact, before the
ketogenic diet, when I was eating all
those carbs, and when I switched over to
beef, oh my goodness, did I feel better.
It was incredible. I no longer had
bloating. And it was really weird
because I thought that you needed fiber
to kind of push things through. But
little did I know that beef really calm
the fire down in my gut. And a lot of
inflammatory conditions went away. I had
arthritis so bad in my hands and my
spine. I had no idea it was connected to
my diet and primarily all the carbs and
grains I was consuming. You just have to
try it. Let's say that you're a vegan
and you want to know what is the best
vegan source of glutamine. Ready for
this?
Cabbage. That's right. Especially red
cabbage. But all cabbage is loaded with
glutamine. So those are the two foods
that have the most glutamine if you were
to look at like just the spectrum of a
meat and a vegetable. And this is also
what I talk about in other videos using
like cabbage for gastritis or an ulcer
or any type of GI inflammatory
condition. Um, you can't really do a lot
of other vegetables and fiber, but
that's the one that most people can deal
with, especially if you do it in a
fermented form, the sauerkraut, because
that way you get all this glutamine from
the the vegetable, but you get the
microbes as well. Now, there are other
things that are loaded with glutamine as
well. You have cheese from either a
sheep or a goat or the um kefir like I
mentioned. You also have eggs and fish
and especially bone broth. Okay, that's
loaded with glutamine. So now I kind of
simplified how to heal your inflammation
and gave you the things that you need to
avoid to really turn this thing around.
I'm telling you, if you have
inflammation, I don't care what kind,
you should start eating these foods,
these I would start basically eating
beef and cabbage and just watch what
happens to your inflammation. And I
think you'll be quite surprised. Now,
because of the censoring and the
suppressing of the algorithms on
YouTube, it's becoming more difficult to
find my content and there's a lot of
content that I cannot put on YouTube,
unfortunately. So, to make sure you have
full access of all my information, go to
dr.com and subscribe to my newsletter by
clicking the link down below in the
description. I will see you on the other
side. Now, if you have not seen my video
on sauerkraut, you should check it out.
I put it up right here. It's actually
very interesting.